Guide to the Rodin Sculpture Garden Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Rodin sculpture garden records
1980-1991
SC0448
Elsen, Albert Edward, 1927-
Stanford University. Department of Art.
4.25 Linear feet
Correspondence, memoranda, proposals, plans, publicity materials, photographs, articles, and other records pertaining to the B. Gerald Cantor Rodin Sculpture Garden. Includes correspondence with the garden's designer Robert Mittelstadt and the personal log of Albert Elsen. An addition to the records (accession 2005-178) includes drafts of the text for the catalog to the Rodin collection, 1988-91 and undated; miscellaneous correspondence, 1985-91; and slides of Rodin works, some of which are copies of old photographs of works in Rodin's studio
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Albert Elsen, 1991, and transfer from art library, 2005.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Through the generosity of B. Gerald Cantor, an outdoor sculpture garden containing works by Auguste Rodin was dedicated at Stanford University in May of 1985. Albert Elsen, professor of art, is curator of the Rodin Collection at Stanford.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, memoranda, proposals, plans, publicity materials, photographs, articles, and other records pertaining to the B. Gerald Cantor Rodin Sculpture Garden. Includes correspondence with the garden's designer Robert Mittelstadt and the personal log of Albert Elsen. An addition to the records (accession 2005-178) includes drafts of the text for the catalog to the Rodin collection, 1988-91 and undated; miscellaneous correspondence, 1985-91; and slides of Rodin works, some of which are copies of old photographs of works in Rodin's studio
Access Terms
Cantor, B. Gerald, 1916-1996; Elsen, Albert Edward, 1927-; Mittelstadt, Robert.; Rodin, Auguste, 1840-1917--Exhibitions.; Stanford University. Department of Art. Faculty.; B. Gerald Cantor Rodin Sculpture Garden (Stanford University).
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Article/JMMC. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Atwater (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bacchetti (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Baker Review (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Benefits (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bing (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Blacher (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brooks - Benches (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - C.F.A Fundraiser - Lights (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cantor (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Changes (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Clubs (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Complaints (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Costs/Budget (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Criticism/Visitors (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Dedication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Dedications (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Development Office (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Docents (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Documentary History, 1980-81 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Documentary History, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Documentary History, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Documentary History, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Documentary History, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Documentary History, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Documentary History, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Donors (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Eitner/Osborne (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fan Letters (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Fan Letters (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fong (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fono Benefit (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Fountain (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Garden Fund, 1984-87 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Garden Fund, 1984-85 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Garden Fund, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Garden Help, S/M/H (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Garden Plan-Final, annotated by AB (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Gates of Hell (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Graham - Flowers (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Green, Vera (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Grove (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Hampton Event (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Herrington (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Inventory, 3/85 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Kurtzon (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Labels (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Leffingwell (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Lighting (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Lists - Corporations and Foundations (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Maintenance, 1985-89 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Middlestadt, Robert; Architect (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Model (Photographs) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Nerrie (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Parking - Article (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Pending Letters (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Perry, Tom (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Plaques (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Pool (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Poster (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Press (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Press Kit with Photographs (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Promotion (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Proposals/ Photographs (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Prospects (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Provost/Dean (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Publicity (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Publicity (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Publicity (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Quad Photos (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Ray (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Rejects (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Rodin by Moonlight (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Rodin Journal, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Security (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Sher/ Photographs (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Shipping (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Smith, John (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Specifications (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Taft/ Trees (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Tours (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Uses (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Photographs, 1984-85 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: Installation of the Gates of Hell, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: Sculpture Garden (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Personal Log of Albert Elsen (Box 7)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-2005-178
  - Rodin catalog, drafts of text: front matter (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rodin catalog, drafts of text: patriotic figures (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rodin catalog, drafts of text: studies for monument to Burghers of Calais (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Rodin catalog, drafts of text: Gates of Hell and their offspring (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Rodin catalog, drafts of text: artists and writers (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Rodin catalog, drafts of text: Balzac essay (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rodin catalog, drafts of text: studies for monuments to Balzac (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Rodin catalog, drafts of text: small figures (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Rodin catalog, drafts of text: partial figures and hands (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Rodin catalog, drafts of text: portraits and symbolic head (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Rodin catalog, drafts of text: miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Rodin catalog, loose items from notebook (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Auction catalog pages of Rodin works (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Contents of computer disks (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Computer floppy disks (5") [2 plastic boxes] (Box 2)
  - Slides of Rodin works, some copied from old photographs of his studio (Box 2)